welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
you
nice I didn't hear anything like at all
I don't know yeah I thought you were on
the phone okay interesting
did you hear my check-ins no yes well
I'll do check-ins
I feel a little stupid now feel a little
like shy barest but then you know my
stoicism is kicking in and said let's
get this show on the road so welcome to
the stove
I'm Peter I think everyone knows that
the steward of the stove off and so this
event it was sort of a spontaneous I
posted it spontaneously and Psyche
didn't know what is gonna be about but
it felt right to do so and we kind of
just figured it out what to do before
4:00 today were even helped me out with
that and so what we're gonna do is Raven
as you probably know I I talk constantly
about this thing called the de mons and
then this is provocative saying like
emancipate the daemon what was he
talking about there so Raven is gonna
ask me some questions to kind of flesh
out some of my thoughts because I need
you know good questions to be fleshed
out and then I'm gonna open up to the
room and then you if you have any
questions or statements just write them
down and then we'll unmute you and then
you read it out and we can kind of have
more of a flowing spontaneous talk about
what happened here and I think the
intention that I'm going in with is sort
of fleshing out what I am sensing into
this project is about of the stoah and
the day one so that thing said I'll hand
it over to ribbons
so Peter today you you published a
letter and you were talking about coming
into your service ISM and bringing forth
this message of emancipating
the daemon can you just begin by setting
the stage for what that means to you and
how you're thinking about it right now
mm-hmm
yeah to speak in the simplest language
it's like there's a I understand the
daemon is like a quality of intuition
that makes you feel most alive if you
follow it and if you listen to it and
there's like a rightness to it as well
but there's also great on knowingness
because you don't know if you follow it
good things are gonna happen there's not
a guarantee and every time I followed
this sort of energy in my life I felt
like an adventure and good things
happened and this whole project for like
a month I've been running on day one
energy and you know just feels I don't
use a word but you know delicious and
it's it just feels really really right
but every time I noticed in the past
when I broke up with this energy with
this Dame on is when the ego kicked in I
got insecure I want to control things
and whatnot and I'm noticed in this
space if you kind of like if you have a
relationship with this energy in
yourself you can see in other people and
then you can double click on their Dame
one I mean so AJ you know he double
clicked on his Damon with his events
with you know Tyson with yourself sort
of just kind of finding what what energy
makes you most alive and then give
people an opportunity to give that gift
and I like the idea this is all this is
being stumbled upon too but the whole
notion of the gift economy which I got
to Andrew at a guard it's like if you
can have that healthy relationship with
the Dame on put aside the ego and just
run with it you will be giving your
greatest gift to the world and I could
be wrong about that but there's feeling
of certainty there when I say it
yeah I think there's other this other
thing that you brought up that was
introduced meeting you and your letter
was the notice year and in connection
with this idea of memetic tribes and so
there's these campfires that are being
list right now these digital campfires
and it seems like the stoah has been
playing a large role in kind of blowing
oxygen into those fires and I see you
making this connection between between
that and mimetic tribes and you talk a
little bit more yeah sure so Dan said no
mysterious it's a motor spear like a
motion motor sphere and a book once that
for a moment but one thing I noticed and
like Collin Morris is a good example of
this so me and Collins chatted you know
we came up with the term existential
dance party because I knew he was a
dancer and then we can I wanted to
invite him in and then the accidental
dance parties were just our freaking hit
you were there at the first one I think
Raven and and then you know I encouraged
Collin to start his own digital campfire
his own like a digital dance studio
where he's inviting all these people and
it's the same model as a stole off a
stop a gifticon to me he's sort of the
steward or whatever similar world he's
talking about he has a bunch of the
scylla taters in the space and then
everyone is getting their gift right and
so this it's this campfire the flames
spread through new campfire and like
you're you and I were talking and you're
gonna do a series of both questions and
abstractions and then the podcast might
emerge from that and then you might have
your own digital campfire you know other
people a Tyson
rheya you know they could find a home
here so that's like a prote like a
incubator for different cyclic
technologies I see this the stoah and
then campfires can emerge and then
people can give their gift to it and I
had this vision where it's just like
just seeing the collective mind and all
these campfire is emerging and I think
that the essence is you light yourself
on fire
then you like the campfire then you find
the others and then you know I was gonna
say then you set the burn
the down but you know
lovingly lovingly yeah I mean it's this
incredible process of bringing more and
more people
into their leadership and their social
connections coming and and catching that
fire from them and then spreading and
it's it's like a mimetic virus but I
also think something that you've been
talking about in your letters and coming
up in the stoah is these practices of
embodiment yes can you talk a little bit
more about that yeah yeah
so you mentioned the motifs fear I'll go
back to that one so there's you know
there's a geosphere and then the
biosphere emerged and then they say then
the noosphere emerged and then let's go
to talk about the biosphere in the
noosphere the biosphere is where you
know genes operate and then the
noosphere or collective consciousness is
where like the memes but I think there's
something in the middle of the Emoto
sphere were of the realm of emotionality
and this is why I always do check-ins
when I when I start with this dough I
just ground myself in in the truth of
the moment and I think what culture were
2.0 my analysis there was that everyone
was being like all these nomadic tribes
attached to their propositions we're
just fighting amongst each other and you
can't win a culture war just doing that
right there's this embodiment there and
I think AJ would like this the guy
interviewed Sam back then who's like
that the narcissist narcissist he says
we're going to we're entering a religion
of narcissism and if you if you think
about it the religion of narcissism is
an ecumenical religion because all these
mathematic tries probably belong to it
if they're you go CLE attach their
propositions in the disembodied so the
ideas once all these digital campfires
start burning
it's like those mimetic tribes will sink
to the becoming body tribes and how does
that happen
culture stealing the culture has jumper
Vicki said in one of the sessions here
and I think we have to steal the culture
as culture that's in service of ego it's
not healthy if you create cultural
artifacts that just serve your own ego
then ya know but if you have a culture
that keeps ego in check
via communitas I think that's the key
and I think there could be many many
variations about it it could be through
dance it could be through education it
could be through freestyle it can be
through philosophy but I think the move
has to be
in order to steal the culture is to
convert mimetic tribes to embody tribes
very powerful um yeah the the question
that's coming up for me right now is how
do we how do we participate with our
egos in a way that allows us to
emancipate our daemon without turning
into the shadow without actually
releasing demons into the world this is
at the edge of my thinking right now
some wonder if you have any thoughts on
that well I mean I think that you're
getting at something when we think about
embodied practices and communitas but
there's a high degree of sovereignty
that people have to already be bringing
and something that I'm seeing that
you're actually maybe the daemon is
working through you in a way is feeling
this kind of excitement for others and
the double clicking process of taking
that excitement and something that could
be turned into an egoic yes perspective
and like these are my people or they
make me cool or they're doing something
for me and actually inviting them to get
their gift it's taking that energy and
bringing it forth and then that invites
someone else to do the very same thing
yeah yeah that's it I find it kind of a
spiritual practice because you know I
won't be shy like I want you to stay at
the store I want AG to stay at the store
you know I want to like I want to have
them all I want to stay them here but no
you know that's not that's not they
won't be giving their gift fully if
that's the case just sort of like a
launching pad that for them to to give
their gift to the world I think that is
the right move and then seeing that grow
is quite beautiful I'm moved by it and
then it's caught as a constant process
of just letting go of the ego too
because like you said it's patches or
whatever like these are like could be
mongrel terms and sloppy like ego Damon
but I think people get what I'm
gesturing at
yeah I think the other thing about this
is that you've been so transparent about
this process and so just available and
it open about how you've been moving
through these arcs and the lessons
you've been learning is that part of
emancipating the daemon you think is
bringing yourselves forth authentically
and talking about how we're wrestling
with these changes yes so I think what
happened - I was talking to Steven
Jenkinson who's a Canadian kind of poet
on death work and that's sort of when
the first kind of like I got a state
shift because he was saying that
basically if you stop being truthful
then you start trying when you
and lie you start trying to control the
minions that you're not supposed to
control and then a dis-ease will spread
through the world and I was like
you talking about covin all that type of
stuff and yeah that's right and so it
became an ethical act for me to be
radically truthful and I'm the
truthfulness muscle is kind of fused to
the damn one right now so I'm just
saying what wants to be said but I'm
saying it with the spirit of
truthfulness but it feels quite
dangerous because it puts you at the
knife edge on a lot of fronts yeah so
there also seems to be this element of
uncertainty that you're acting before
you have a certainty about whether or
not the outcome is what you intend it to
be for what you want and do you feel
that the daemon energy actually allows
for that to happen and how do we invite
that in how do we like let ourselves
be at the night's edge and still make
decisions that have real world's
implications yeah I think one thing is
coming up there's just kind of now I
think if more of us are at the knife's
edge you'll be easier to be there
because we can support each other
communitas and there's a balance like
Socrates you know the wisest the wisest
man it's like he knew he knew he knew
nothing right so there's there's this
like propped on a propositional level
it's being able to rest in radical
unknowingness
but then without Damon energy it's
radical knowingness and knowing how to
like hold both those two together is an
art form that I am trying to discover
right now yeah can you talk about the
role of questions and asking the right
question and how that's been how can you
navigate through this experience I think
you're the expert on this one so maybe I
could balance that question back at you
well I think especially since the gift
economy talk by Andrew Taggert the
question of what gift do you want to
give or what question wants to be asked
has been coming in and out of lots of
conversations and themes and be
integrated embodied through a practice
there's a way of taking questioning as
an abstraction as a way of like sorting
and cutting pieces of reality into
categories is a level that you can
understand it in an abstract sense but
to begin to practice the act of
questioning and then to get into the
meta side of it to be like oh it's not
this question and I'm attached to but
actually the depression behind that
which is what question is should be
asked like what should be good given
yeah and I know it's just like a fool
arising in me right now so a lot of
people are saying like walk eh you get
more rest you should do this you should
do that and I'm like why and then the
question that comes out for me when
people are saying that like can you
measure wisdom
can wisdom be measured and if the
question is the the foundation of wisdom
like wise old Socrates says can you
measure the most effective question I
don't think so so what do you rely on
and if you you know you read your Plato
Socrates relied on his Dale on his
guiding spirit so and eudaimonia the
Greek word but people translate for
happiness is having a good relationship
with your Damon good ammonia so yeah I
think having the good the right question
is the foundation but with you ask the
question without wanting anything in a
way without trying to engineer without
trying to manipulate without trying to
control you just asked the question that
wants to be asked and I think that's the
foundation yes it's like a bringing
together of like the questioning or the
ability to like give voice to the
invisible and bringing it down into the
intuitive so that you can like speak
from your truth speaks for your
intellect but be coming from a place of
truthfulness and right relationship with
that Damon energy that doesn't need to
know before it does you know that can
just do yes yeah and and with the
subjective questions we've got some
really good questions coming in the chat
I just jump in because I have
I don't like how the session is going
and I think this is the right way but if
this is going to be a weekly thing I
kind of like the idea I don't want this
to be a freaking Peter show that's the
last thing I want it to be right I want
us all in this together figuring out how
to emancipate the Dame one not only
ourselves but everyone else's
so that's my hope for these sessions I
just I just you know I don't usually
take the spotlight but I think that felt
right right now taking it that's why I
think I was a little bit nervous coming
into this session yeah that's a lot to
be in the spotlight it's I would just
say and to respond to that that like
your emancipation of your Damon has very
much helped emancipate mine and I can
see it doing that with other people and
it's an incredible experience to be with
this community where we're really rising
up into our like possible selves and
through communitas like their community
and it's it's very uncanny that we can
come together intuitively and do this
right now and when I hear that you know
sort of like almost tears are welling up
and just felt really good hearing this
are you ready for questions all right
thank you for doing this Peter let's see
if I could find my question here okay
does I read many many a long time ago I
read Hermann Hesse's Damian and I was
wondering if this concept of Damon or
diamond or eudaimonia relates in any way
to the from what I remember there was
sort of this female character in the
story that he kept recognizing or seeing
and was attracted to and was following
and I got somehow the sense that this
was somehow related to the Jungian
concept of this was the the anima the
female spirit within his male spirit or
something like this this may
my own projection and I'm wondering have
any thoughts yeah that's that's really
great um that's my favorite book of all
time I was addicted to Hermann Hesse her
HESA when I was younger and I probably
that was a book I read most my whole
life is Damian yeah I didn't like I got
to read it again because I don't
remember like he was talking with the
animal there but it makes sense to me
now that that he was see I have a deep
connection with that that book thank you
all right next question from Dominus
that's a question maybe a statement but
you can share your statement - hmm so
listening to you talking about
emancipating Damon I hope everyone can
hear me I woke up to something with the
question of how to emancipate the daemon
without waking up demons I don't think
you can do it I think you can't do it
because the demons will always be part
of you and they're part of your strength
they're like your shadow you have to
integrate them you have to invite them
to the campfire - just like we would
have invited wolves wolves to the
campfire and tamed the things that we
fear in them to our own service if you
ignore them or fear them and make
enemies of those parts of yourself they
just move into the basement of your soul
and start lifting weights
well-put I can't take credit for that
when that was Amanda Palmer could you uh
send that to me I really love that
absolutely absolutely she said it in an
interview with Tim Ferriss it was very
good that's beautiful
yeah yeah and I agree my experience
recently is that if you follow the the
Dame on it puts you at the knife's edge
and then you start meeting demons and I
can talk about the whole demon concept
and more sex
their terms - don't forget all Christian
but like my therapist was Jordan
Peterson so like I kind of go to
Christian mythology sometimes and it
seems like there's a grammar there that
that's works somewhat and I'm realizing
that if you're at the knife's edge and
then you encounter these demons you very
well better be virtuous are they
gonna get you so it's like opportunity
to practice your virtue and so this is
sort of like you know perfect
opportunity practice my stoicism thanks
for that that was amazing yeah and I
think that's feels really right that
when you emancipate your daemon the
demons show up - and you have to face
the shadow and maybe then the wrong move
that has been made over and over and
over again is to turn away from those
things and then like you said they just
grow stronger in the basement and
forgotten dreams and it's interesting
how so much mythology I think has been
coming up and here and I have been kind
of exchanging stories like talking about
how Orpheus has to go down to Hades to
recover you're rid of seeds and yet his
like shadow comes his doubt and he looks
back at her and the thing that he
desired most that he liked sacrificed
himself to go and recover his lost
forever you know there's so many stories
but talk about this this like power that
that's and also investing like I think
the idea of the anima or like the figure
of the woman who draws you beyond your
hesitation and emancipates you and gets
you to act beyond what you know what
will happen and then all of the trouble
that kind of comes from that and the
virtue that you need to actually make it
through experience that all just came up
and what you were saying and that's
great that's great that also to share
yeah thanks man I really appreciate that
I also recommend checking out Zak
Stein's article and he came under still
to talk about it war broke out in heaven
and hell
I think which is related we have another
question from Khalil
do you wanna unmute yourself hold on one
second
good yeah there we go
yeah wow those those so many things just
derailed my original question there so I
guess I'll sneak in another one I
originally asked do you have any fear
that one morning you'll listen for the
demo and you won't hear anything is that
something that you think is a class like
even a remote possibility or you have
any fear regarding on I think it's a
possibility I don't have any fear about
it what happened when this whole thing
that I triggered it really I had I told
some people this bad some bad news
personally before I still honest OA and
then I was devastated like what I'm
gonna do with my life now and then you
couldn't cove it happen I was I put that
house to act like and then I and I had
this kind of like existential breakdown
like wow I don't know how to
with my life you know like 35 years old
I don't have my life I read every single
philosopher looking at the hands on all
these self-help books spiritual
practices nothing and then there's Jason
thought that occurred there is like huh
no one else knows how to live my life
either right and so how do I get into
right relationship with not knowing how
to live my life and then that judgment
always there if not only hell live my
life just kind of like just disappeared
I'm like huh you know this day one
energy that keeps coming back it might
have something so I just basically
handed the keys over to it yeah so that
that sort of so I don't think it's gonna
go anytime soon but yeah I'm not really
afraid if it doesn't either
if if I could just ask a follow-up like
I noticed like when
this topic comes up or the idea of being
vulnerable comes up my I could feel my
body like tingling or shaking a bit I
guess so I was wondering it you had to
come overcome any physiological
reticences or just physiological
barriers to to getting a right
relationship with your Dame oh yeah and
like Damon's not asking me to sleep
sometimes and I'm gonna remind it of
like those those a Orthodox Christian
that's why I was baptized that they had
like Desert Fathers
and how they was like you know went to
the desert and didn't eat didn't sleep
and so they they got closer to God type
thing and so I was like I made a joke
like leave I'm a digital desert father
just sort of like not getting out of my
head right and just kind of lose just
following that energy I think that's
dangerous obviously two dollars not too
much but I don't I answered your
question that's what came up part of the
embodiment of this is like you can take
concepts like I mean even if you were to
unpack game and even unpack that and
explain it and some sort of categorical
way physiological response integrating
those concepts that we do actually have
to confront with and contend with
because that like prickling sensation of
like fever that moves throughout your
body will stop you you know it'll close
your throat up it'll like prevent you
from emancipating
you know that energy and I think that's
part of the move into bravery is like
you just have to do it even though your
heart is like pumping and you're kind of
freaking out you just go for it and try
and then I think that that maybe is like
I don't wear the nice edge is you're
like standing on the precipice of
something and pushing forward without
falling over into the abyss that it's
cutting through which by the way
I miss Donna's question and I'd like for
her to ask it Donna if you want to ask
your question yeah just very simply I'm
kind of new to this group and I'm very
interested in your experience of the
knife's edge in a way that would help
define it for me yeah the term came from
I was writing copy for the website and
then Andrew Taggart I meant to reviewed
it and he put razor's edge and I quite
like that and then somehow nice edge
came up I change it the nice edge and
then I use that as my opening and then I
got a rap name by Nicolas he called me
the knife's edge and I quite liked that
it made sense and I felt into it more
and I'm like oh ads yeah knife's
edge is perfect because I'm always
feeling up out of the nice edge right
now in order to have this right
relationship with the Dame one it was
like you got to be at the nice edge you
got to be virtuous you know you've gotta
like challenge of demons you gotta do
all that type of stuff so it really
feels like you're given a nice edge if
you if you want to be in right
relationship with this so I just
stumbled on the term and then it feels
like that's right for that reason
there's a few questions here both people
having resistance to still the culture
and I'm curious to hear it yeah Valerie
do yourself and ask your question yeah
so now I feel like I'm being looked at
okay so as I'm listen to what you're
saying and right that the words sound
familiar to me but like it feels kind of
familiar
it just looks familiar you using like
different language but the meaning is
familiar to me so I'm particularly
trying to understand what you mean by
still in the culture so what culture why
still and still and from whom
I'm curious
first of all I like seeing you as you as
you know this is good seeing you again
my friend
and yeah I'm curious if there's any
reason why you asked that just so I can
kind of feel into the question more
because like I don't know what does it
mean is it is it implies action like for
example like maybe it's a good time to
to start speaking like I like Jordan
didn't like and he mentions like speak
up and if you like it like take
responsibility and things happen and I
have experience with that so is it the
same or is it like let's say referring
to the duration of media we're creating
something you hear something real
authentic okay
so sorry I did did you just help yeah
yeah so what's coming up for me is um
yeah that was helpful it's like one hand
I say like I'm not too concerned about
the terms I use like like there's better
language than Damon then I would use it
but I had a historical relationship with
it the Socrates the book theme you know
a type of stuff so that's why I'm
connected with it but I think what
people are hearing it they feel what's
behind it and that's why I Peterson and
Peterson as I mentioned he's like my
therapist for two years and people hate
him I love him but they felt him right
he wasn't this disembodied blue Church
intellectual yet idiot type type person
he spoke from a source and he spoke from
that energy or some energy and so I
wouldn't like don't focus too much on
the propositional level I say that focus
on the energy behind it and what does it
say to you or what do you feel like and
maybe what terms work better for you
when you feel into that energy so that's
coming up for me something
I wanted to say yeah I think Peterson
his shadow was postmodernism like he
couldn't go to the portion Laden realm
this is why I really like like Raven
because she can get to this abstract
like Metis space and very few people can
like get there and plate with it
comfortably but I think in this liminal
war that were entering into where all
these narratives are just flying no one
knows what's going on radical
uncertainty you had to have that like
healthy postmodern skill set in order to
navigate this space and not be so
attached to propositional terms but make
sure you have the sort of relationship
with the energy behind each proposition
like you can sink you can play in the
noosphere but you can also sink in the
motor sphere and you can go back and
forth between the two came up for me
when we were talking about the stealing
the culture was maybe a better or maybe
an enlarged ISM that works what well for
me is actually seduced the culture hmm
to draw things in like to draw people
into the light I mean the campfire right
is this kind of beacon if you're in the
dark you don't know where you're going
and you see a glimmer of fire in the
distance that draws you in it's like an
act of seduction and that kind of thing
is not zero-sum like that's something
that isn't stealing in the same sense
it's stealing in a maybe metaphorical or
a loose sense there's a way that the
fire is stealing but no human is doing
the stealing like the fire itself draws
you in yes no that's perfect
and it feels almost like that's a
feminine way to put it and the masculine
way stealing it because I like the the
stealing term because John rebecky came
up with that and a cure the DA is gonna
do a theme song on steal at that clip so
there's gonna be actual official theme
song I'm stealing the culture which is
awesome and I like the idea of stealing
it because you know a thief does not
come announced he just takes and he
takes effectively he doesn't make a big
show of it and that's what I think this
project should be about like let's not
broadcast it's not like oh my God look
at us we're awesome right cuz that's
just gonna track all the Eagle of noise
and we don't want it and then once
things get established and then we're
dancing around the fire released
rapping we're getting high on oxytocin
then we're gonna seduce people in to
become embodied so yeah I think that is
a dual motto of this this space yeah and
I think to like the idea of the thief
can also be thought of as trickster you
know there's there's kind of a way that
thief or steal maybe appeals to a
certain kind of person a certain kind of
warrior energy somebody who feels like
against things and kind of like
subversive and I think maybe seducing or
I'm drawing in is a little bit or
trickster is like trickster is is
playing with the magic of the world and
like like creating through this
alchemical process and making mistakes
and like twisting things around and does
steal yes that is so so good
because this is a synchronicity moment
so Daniel a defect II was in the room
he mentioned like oh yeah we can talk
about sort of these like maybe this
primordial language of the Dame on all
this stuff but we need the skill set of
pomo as like a marketing thing right
because you gotta find the right
language to hit and you know the
postmodern language by itself isn't
neutered it's a dead end but if you use
it playfully it has that trickster
quality and just when I got that that
insight I reached out to my friend
Alexander barb who is the archetype of
the trickster he's coming on the stoah I
have to apologize to him publicly I want
to steal publicly because I don't think
I did I was not a good friend to him at
one point but he's coming on and and I
just just in time we need the trickster
yeah and I think like trickster thief
and fool are a kind of triad that kind
of encompassed this this way of being
that you kind of need to dance between
all three of those aspects there has to
be this a level of which you can laugh
at yourself or smile and maybe that's a
way that we let go I want the ego as
well is this ability to just be the fool
and to like dance around oh you know all
the naked kings who like take themselves
so seriously and reveal like the the
joke
of what's happening that everyone else
can't see yeah and what's coming up
there it's like I have a tendency for
gravitas taking myself too seriously
this is why I like putting my knife edge
is doing like larae it was like the
oxytocin party like just being a freakin
goof and fool with these activities and
just loving it so yeah I definitely
agree with that
wonderful okay there's lots of things
happening in the chat yeah so we have
Daniel do you want to bring forth your
question sure you folks this is about
nickname by the way you should see him
every Saturday at this freestyle depict
in so Peter my question to you and to
you to Raven if you have any insight
into this how does one mitigate demonic
false positives so an example could be
your ego is taking over and it's
masquerading as intuitive wisdom there
was a suggestion earlier that communitas
could act as a regulatory force here
then the question kind of goes is not
another level how do you regulate
communitas yeah so we were texting about
this Daniel I need propositional
violence I need people to disagree with
me aggressively and I think people need
to be disagreed with aggressively but
sort of in like a safe on safe space in
order to keep each other in check so
we're not get too eagerly attached to
propositions an interpretation of what
the energy is going interview happening
so that that's my take and I'm curious
what Raven has to think about that yeah
it's a complex question I would say that
once you get above the level of
community oz you know you're kind of
want to be meaning on the emergence of
into like individual actors embodying
that those qualities to try and enforce
it top down I think would be a way of
trying to take some abstraction and
regulate the behavior but we need to
kind of move from a bottom up position
in order to create this emergent
property of checks and balances
Alexandra bardos actually talks a lot
about
things coming in threes there being
these kinds of like structures or
movement between different aspects of
things that allow for things anyone
proposition to be seen as incomplete
without being challenged by these two
other sides of things and I think that
there are ways that maybe intuitively as
we move through this like new really
like uncertain place we're kind of
creating and experimenting I think as
individuals being really sensitive to
feedback and also allowing for people to
express authentically when they're
experiencing shadow emotions that's
really important to be able to say like
yeah you know I'm when you do that I
feel jealous of you
or when when you do that I feel like I
want to grab you or whatever it is that
you're experiencing allows for that to
come forth and be shared in the space in
between people and you can reveal the
shadow it's like you take the thing that
normally we would feel ashamed to to say
and we allow for that to be a subject of
the dialogue of the community Oz and
think if we practice those things and we
move you know in a small scale and I
think the splitting off two is effective
because if you try and grow the same
group larger and larger you'll start to
face different challenges as the group
size scales up but if you just break off
into little pieces you have a group of
five and then it grows to 10 and then it
splits into two fives then you're kind
of able to maintain the platoon scale
kind of like mobile dynamic wave and we
need that because the climate is so
uncertain we're not really ready to be
building institutions yet but rather
just maintaining these platoons I think
Rachel had a really good question in
here that I was I was interested in
Rachel would you like to share yes so
I'm thinking about masculine stealing
feminine seducing if they mean the same
things in different contexts
some if one is public and the other is
private when we're talking about like
keeping things close they're not letting
everybody know is there maybe like a
masculine private and a feminine public
going on here hmm that's really good
what do you think Rachel um I think
there might be higher and in other
places and I'm starting to think that it
could be an adaptive behavior where like
less fierce like Strauss talk about
keeping things secretive and maybe
there's a feminine energy that helps
conceal things in a softer way uh is
needed or a public interfacing right now
yeah that feels really really right I
want to get to thank you Rachel I think
that's a really good thing to be
thinking about and I've been thinking
about it a lot the role of feminine and
unknown space to traverse in terms of
the feminine being realized this is an
entirely new territory there's been a
kind of I mean I guess it depends on
what like like vein of feminism any you
know anybody's adopted but certainly
we've like created structures around
like the role of the feminine in society
that seem to be failing not only women
but everyone and moving forward into a
place of greater like maturation of of
the feminine seems like it's just never
been done before in human history
seems like a seems like a brand-new
thing which means there's no role models
I mean I think that that's the challenge
here with with moving into like the
female like maturity is like well who do
you who are your elders who embodies
this because I mean
the the power of like coming into
oneself with technology like with
digital technology and with what's
coming with more immersive technologies
into the future is just such a different
way of expressing and being in the world
and I think is it's polluted and is
spatial and is rooted in images and like
communication that is indirect which is
the communication of the feminine and to
be moving into that and being in right
relationship with it when there are all
these other kinds of dynamics of
commodification of sexual ization of
like self annihilation that comes from
being in social media there's so many so
many shadows to be moving out as as a
feminine entity into the world so yeah
those things have been on my mind is
long I just wanna say really cool to
have like Raven Rachael Ray Donna and
all the kind of the feminine energy in
this place cuz I don't know what what's
going on there you know like that's not
my language I'm tapped into but I would
really want to be in right relationship
with it so for me personally a lot of
times when I try to tap into my mom when
I'm in different conversations I have
very like I'm very into like edgy memes
and so I sometimes like this one
only say the worst thing yeah like good
at the time and this kind of this kind
of so I'm wondering if you've
experienced this sometimes the daemon
can be very sort of like banned allistic
and it's in this direction and if you
experience that like what do you think
about that and how do you deal with it
and so on
yeah like daniel said like the daemon is
a troll and all that yeah like there's a
like a desire to give advice and I also
kind of know you too like Jordans in
Toronto like I've seen some of the
things he wears that has that kind of
like trollish flair to it which I won't
name but maybe maybe Daniel my sense
they not as a good good response to
Jordans
on the spot here you said the daemon as
a troll in the chatbox maybe you could
elaborate on that I think sometimes it's
it's the right thing like I I don't know
I read Socrates as a troll and he's kind
of going around poking and prodding
people and getting them to wake up the
question is like what's your false
positive or false negative right it's
always gonna come down to that and
sometimes you're you're like a bad troll
and sometimes your control and perhaps
the daemon also gets trained over time
perhaps it's all about you can develop a
relationship with your daemon but the de
menthe itself is not actually aiming in
the right direction but throughout your
life it gets better and better at aiming
in the right direction
yeah and I also add it's like you know
you'd that trollish tendency could have
a demonic quality to it but who the
egoic so like look at me look at me I'm
not these like you know there's social
justice people or whatever that don't
know what's going on so there could be
the attention-seeking things there I
imagine I'm curious with ajaces chaotic
good versus chaotic evil kind of a
twitter meme that's been happening
that's coming to mind and I think it
connects to the trickster energy just a
desire to shake things up and for me
it's always connected to wanting people
to see outside of their their culture or
their conditioning and that the
trickster the chaotic good or evil or
the troll even it's like this longing
for people to just break out of their
boxes and see the world in any kind of
new way that's what's coming up for me
and a gem and the spire to ask you a
question because you're ashamed you
cater here in Toronto and you're like
kicking ass in the stove and all these
like cool events the stuff that you
heard today having spoken about the Dame
on and relation with ego and stuff how
do you think that what is your sense of
how that relates a shame
I kind of interpret you Peter as having
a had a shame breakthrough where I don't
know what happened in your life but
there was a moment where you
couldn't be bothered to care what people
thought as much anymore and it freed you
to just follow some kind of passion but
said do this and you're like okay I'll
do it then you called that your daemon
and that's how I interpret it that I had
a shame breakthrough moment as well
there are these moments where for
whatever reason we just can't be
bothered to care enough about all these
other people's opinions and expectations
and then we kind of feel free to just be
ourselves and like I look at shame as
the mitigating wall between the real me
and the outside world and shame says
don't show them that
show them this or this and when you have
that breakthrough you just have a
channel where you can kind of be you
know more direct and sometimes it is
like as Jordan was saying it's like
either glia stuff that I'm not supposed
to say yeah sometimes it's just the real
like real emotional authentic truths
that you just always hide that's what
and when I was hearing talk I was
hearing the daemon talk right there cuz
that was delicious you know I just like
my body was filled with like foo mos and
then I want double-click on something
you said a shame breakthrough that could
be a really good workshop if we can kind
of like figure out how to do that shame
breakthrough and I think if I knew how
to bottle that what's the matter is
entirely my goal is how do you help
people have a breakthrough moment where
they have the freedom to be themselves
Oh AJ like because agent I were going
back and forth about trying to figure
out a weekly session that maybe could be
it Shane breakthrough or you just
radically experiment on how to do that
yeah I love that I mean that's my life
is trying to figure out how most
directly to explain to someone what I
experienced and to find out do they need
to experience that could they experience
that is there an opportunity there have
they already experienced it what other
ways could you have a breakthrough
that's like
my whole dream so I love that idea let's
do that and see what happens here there
were just AJ and I that was like the
Damon speaking to itself through to
people in a way and I've been having
these conversations with everyone really
who's coming in as a distill atutor to
the stoah so I think it's like an art
form in a way if you can speak to this
this language you can speak it with
other people and you can unlock it and
then you can emancipate it it might be
like creative force right like when two
minds come together and run a few Minds
come together and you're just like in
sync and in flow and it's just like
really creating new Sparks and new
possible places like that seems to be
another way to explain the Damon and
speaking of changing things and shaking
things up a bit
Isaiah's do you want to bring forth your
question yeah so in reading your your
journal entries Peter I keep thinking
about the article you wrote culture war
2.0 pointing to a lot of of the Occupy
movement that's like one of the I guess
the UH
like it just like it set off a like a
depolarization in the culture and I like
thinking a lot about movies in the
matrix in this whole like DejaVu
switching the matrix thing we're
currently we're big businesses are being
bailed out and it's literally impossible
to form that kind of movement right now
so I'm wondering if you think that the
emancipation of the damemon can can help
us like be engineer such movement and
maybe even to like and the law I mean I
don't want to because I constantly keep
thinking now this lockdown will only end
through some sort of like mass active
social of civil disobedience like if if
if the people in charge like they have
if they don't listen to the demon or if
they don't have these types of things
like why would they give up this power
they currently have yeah
and what comes to mind is conversation I
have with Jordan Hall recently sojourn
was a friend of mine he's been mentoring
me for a while and I just said to him
like you know what I don't feel your
heart you know like he talks in
abstraction and it feels like almost a
propositional prison he's putting on to
me because he's a highly smart he's
probably like the Olympic level athlete
in in the noosphere but doesn't speak
with his heart and he agreed with me
says yeah I get that advice a lot and I
find I had rizona out when you talk
sometimes and I'm like ten metaphors to
understand as metaphor I think him and I
are getting in right relationship
speaking of the heart together but why
he came to mind is that I don't think we
need an answer in the propositional
realm
I think we still have to stay in that
state of unknowingness and my sense we
just take it one step at a time and then
anything will emerge one more question
okay some really good ideas in here for
how to emancipate your daemon improv
sessions this is what like I gazing so I
don't even know what's going on here
this is exactly what I wanted right like
this type of idea is just kind of
flooding in this is the day one speaking
right now okay I guess I guess so yeah
something I'll say that maybe it's time
to time to go but I have another event
coming up called building the stoah
that's on the weekend Sunday I need help
here right it's like a one-man operation
right now and I'm burning out and if you
don't let me go insane then maybe you'd
be good to you don't lend a hand with
something and so if you're inspired to
do that just go to build into stoah on
weekend and we kind of discussed
practical things there's all these like
practical ideas like someone said oh I
want to continue this discussion and
let's have like an after party zoom link
in the chat because that can't be here
so that hasn't after that's great I
don't know how to amend that and maybe I
don't need to maybe that could be
outsourced to some kind of like culture
that forms out of it
so I like this idea is like maybe these
two sessions relate to each other that
one's is practical like the nuts and
bolts of it like
how to do better than that management
how to do better like advertisement and
stuff like that and then this one is
sort of like sourcing the idea like
emancipating it slowly and I will say -
like I'm not gonna post this one
broadcast it I will maybe make it
unlisted and send everyone a link to it
and then I'll let you use your
discernment on who you send it to and
try not to send it on the ego because a
good thief doesn't come announced Oh
we're wrapping up here later today we're
having a talk by Rachel haywire and
Rachel happens to be in the room Rachel
do you want to tell us a little bit
about what your talk is gonna be about
later today sure so I'm giving a talk on
building and aesthetic movement we're
gonna discuss art music literature the
role that these forms of creative
expression have during a pandemic we're
just during a time of chaos and maybe
tap in to this energy but we've been
discussing and how to let out the primal
artistic self and it was like an act of
serendipity - like when I posted the
event I'm like oh like Rachel's
events right after this is perfect yeah
weed art right now we need an aesthetic
movement yeah I actually I came up with
a new topic for my talk just based on
the meeting that we just had about how
to say what you can't say in a creative
way that doesn't necessarily get Liat
people like how to channel that that's
the right level mm-hmm yeah that's
that's good alright so uh let's close
out here thank you everyone for for this
discussion that was really good a lot of
ideas and good energy I feel the energy
I feel the day one collectively and
thanks Raven for prodding me with your
great a level the tight game tight
question game from Raven yes I
appreciate that
that being said I have to go and yeah I
think you everyone knows the drill here
and I just feel a lot of preciate so
thanks everyone